It's bigger than Imperial nobles' mansions.
這裡比帝國貴族的豪宅還要大啊
Oh my.
哎呀
Uncle Polka, welcome back.
波爾卡叔叔 歡迎回來
(POLKA'S NEPHEW, SHIZUKI SHINOYAMA, 11 YEARS OLD) I bet you were going to run away directly.
(波爾卡的姪子 四乃山紫月 11歲) 我還賭你會直接逃掉呢
(POLKA'S NIECE, KAZUKI SHINOYAMA, 11 YEARS OLD)
(波爾卡的姪女 四乃山華月 11歲)
Uh-huh.
嗯
Because I had promised someone.
畢竟我和人約好了
Oh my, oh my.
哎呀哎呀
I never expected you
沒想到
to shamelessly come back.
你居然恬不知恥地回來了
(POLKA'S NEPHEW, SHINOYAMA SECURITY PRESIDENT) (TAKERU SHINOYAMA, 26 YEARS OLD)
(波爾卡的姪子 四乃山警備社長) (四乃山尊 26歲)
Weren't you on a journey to find yourself?
你不是“踏上尋找自我的旅途”了嗎
I found a brand new self in Shinjuku.
我在新宿找到了全新的自己
Anyway,
那麼
who is the young lady next to you?
可以請你解釋一下 站在你身邊的那位小姐是怎麼回事嗎
She is…
她是…
Nice to meet you.
初次見面
I'm Misaki Sakimiya.
我是崎宮美咲
It's a pleasure to meet you.
往後請多關照
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《屍體如山的死亡遊戲》
Unexpectedly, you actually gave up
(第6集 The Firestarter -赴火之蟲-) 沒想到妳居然會因為波爾卡
the idea of suicide because of Polka.
而放棄自殺的念頭
Yes.
是啊
If it weren't for polka,
若不是波爾卡
I might not be alive today.
如今我可能已經不在世上了
Since then,
自那之後
Polka has numerous times saved me.
我也曾多次被波爾卡所救
It seems that he truly "found a brand new self".
他口中的“找到了全新的自己” 看來是真的啊
However,
不過
I never expected that the young lady
我沒想到“崎宮鋼鐵”的大小姐
from Sakimiya Steel would actually be with you.
居然會和你在一起
Sakimiya Steel no longer exists.
崎宮鋼鐵這家公司已經不存在了
I misspoke.
是我失言了
I was fortunate to have received a lot of care from your parents in the past,
我過去曾承蒙妳父母諸多照顧
and it's regrettable that
他們竟然遭遇了那種事
they had to go through such a terrible thing.
我真的感到很遺憾
Rozan is the head of the Shinoyama family.
四乃山家的家主呂算
His eldest son, Gaku Shinoyama, is 48 years old.
他的大兒子四乃山岳48歲
Rozan's second wife later gave birth to Polka you,
呂算的繼室後來生下了波爾卡
the second son 30 years younger than his elder son.
也就是說 你是和他的大兒子 年齡相差30多歲的次子
And your nephew, Takeru Shinoyama.
另外還有你的姪子四乃山尊
Among the relatives in Polka,
在波爾卡的親戚中
he is considered a very scary person.
這傢伙是一個極為可怕的人
He is the president of Shinoyama Security.
他是四乃山警備的社長
SHINOYAMA SECURITY? MOST OF THE PEOPLE THERE ARE REHIRED POLICE OFFICERS
(四乃山警備嗎 那裡大多是空降的警察)
WHOSE MAIN JOB IS TO ELIMINATE SCANDALS AND CLEAR OUT TROUBLEMAKERS.
(工作內容主要為 消除醜聞以及清理礙事的傢伙)
IT IS SAID THAT THE SHINOYAMA GROUP HAS AN ASSASSINATION TEAM
(據說四乃山集團有一支暗殺部隊)
CONTROLLED BY TAKERU SHINOYAMA.
(由四乃山尊在一手操控)
You know it very well.
你知道得真詳細啊
The reason why he's considered scary
要說他為什麼可怕
is mainly that he took charge of such an organization
主要是因為他僅僅26歲
at the young age of 26.
就掌管了這樣一個組織
You must have had a tough time.
妳應該過得很不容易吧
If you encounter any difficulties,
如果妳遇到了什麼困難
feel free to come to us for help.
可以來找我們幫忙喔
Kiri,
希吏
don't make promises about other people's lives at will.
妳不要隨便對他人的人生許下許諾
Oh.
哎呀
What's wrong with this, Takeru?
這有什麼不好的呢 尊
(TAKERU'S WIFE, KIRI SHINOYAMA, 24 YEARS OLD) Isn't it great that it feels like
(尊的妻子 四乃山希吏 24歲) 這樣就像我們多了個家人一樣
we have gained a new family member?
不是很棒嗎
I am reminding you
我是在提醒妳
not to ignore the other party's thoughts and say whatever you like.
不要無視對方的想法自說自話
Anyway, you are a friend of my family,
不管怎樣
so I naturally welcome you.
妳是我家人的朋友 我自然歡迎
You don't have to be restrained and can be more casual.
妳不用拘謹 可以隨意些
Your kindness leaves me humbled and grateful.
您的厚愛讓我不勝惶恐
She's amazing. Her response was impeccable.
好厲害 她的回覆滴水不漏
I also need to work hard to not reveal anything.
我也得努力不露餡才行啊
It took me a whole night to remember the dining etiquette.
我花了一晚上 大致上記住了餐桌禮節
What's the deal with that shark plush toy?
那個鯊魚玩偶是怎麼回事
It seems like it moves from time to time.
它好像時不時在動
Hmm… This is…
呃 這個是…
Berg, the shark of hell.
“地獄鯊魚伯格”
Sis Sayo.
小夜姐
That design was
那種設計
(POLKA'S NIECE, UNEMPLOYED, SAYO SHINOYAMA, 20 YEARS OLD) the climax version
(波爾卡的姪女 無業 四乃山小夜 20歲) 是第二部的頂級版本
and it can be considered a masterpiece until the third one.
直到第三部為止那部都堪稱名作
However, now that Shark Berg has evolved into a completely humanoid form,
可如今鯊魚伯格進化為完全的人形
the shark-like appearance is gone. Physiologically, I can't accept it.
外型設計徹底失去了鯊魚這一要素 就生理層面而言我難以接受
Nevertheless, I personally think that the artificial shark girl
不過第五部出場的人造鯊魚美少女
who appeared in the fifth part is not bad.
我個人覺得還不錯
But in the end, Shark Berg…
但是鯊魚伯格最後從嘴裡…
But speaking of which, fortunately, young master Polka is safe and sound.
不過話說回來 幸好波爾卡少爺平安無事
Oh? Yeah, that's right.
啊也是呢
Who is he?
他是誰
Is he my relative?
我的親戚嗎
What's his name?
名字是什麼
(RELATIVE, NEPHEW-IN-LAW OF ROZAN SHINOYAMA, 52 YEARS OLD) It seems that you are
(親戚 四乃山呂算的姪女婿 52歲) 看來您的精力
even more energetic than your father.
比您父親大人還要旺盛啊
May I ask, where are the others?
請問 其他人呢
They are all working, of course.
他們當然是在工作了
Father and Mother are both abroad.
父親大人和母親大人都在國外
The only ones staying here today are
今天留在這裡的
Bro Takeru who happened to be on day off,
只有碰巧休假的尊哥哥
Sis Kiri
還有希吏姐姐
and Sis Sayo who is not working.
以及沒有工作的小夜姐姐
I am the "guardian of my own room",
我是“自己房間的警衛”
unable to take care of the whole family.
沒法顧及到全家
And then there are kids like us.
再來就是像我們這樣的小孩子了
Hey, Kazuki.
喂喂 華月
How could you forget about me, the head of the family?
妳怎麼能把我這個家長給忘了啊
(SHINOYAMA GROUP'S LEADER, ROZAN SHINOYAMA, 79 YEARS OLD) I, as your Grandpa, will cry,
(四乃山集團當家 四乃山呂算 79歲) 爺爺我可是會哭的喔
Grandpa,
爺爺
are you able to walk?
您可以下地走路了嗎
Hmm, I'm feeling pretty good today.
嗯 我今天感覺還不錯
By the way, Sayo.
對了 小夜
What's up?
什麼事
That movie you recommended before,
之前妳推薦我看的那部
"The Shallows,"
叫《絕鯊島》的電影
was quite interesting.
還蠻有趣的
Really?
是嗎
That's good.
那就好
Next time you can try "47 Meters Down" or "Bait".
下次你可以試試《深海鯊機》 或者《大海嘯鯊口逃生》
All of them are movies related to sharks.
全部都是跟鯊魚有關的電影啊
President,
會長
it's great to hear that your health is gradually improving.
您的身體能逐漸好轉 真是太好了
You came at the right time
您來得正好
I wanted to talk about the pharmaceutical department with you.
我正好想跟您商量一下製藥部門的事
As I am currently in a semi-retired state,
我現在是半退休的狀態
you can approach Gaku for further discussions on this matter.
你要商量事情 就去找岳吧
Yes, but…
話是這樣說沒錯
Hey,
喂
do you want me to say it again?
你想讓我再說一遍嗎
I'm…I'm really sorry.
十…十分抱歉
Grandpa.
爺爺
Don't make that kind of expression.
別露出那種表情嘛
If it's an emergency,
要是事態緊急
I will listen to him in person.
我會當面聽他講講的
So, Polka…
那麼 波爾卡
Yes…
我…我在
You must have something to say.
你應該有什麼話要說吧
Um… I'm really sorry for leaving home
那個 我不打招呼就離開家
without saying goodbye.
真的很抱歉
Not this, stupid.
你說錯啦 笨蛋
You should say, "I'm back".
你首先要說“我回來了”才對吧
I'm back.
我回來了
Regarding the matter of that young lady,
至於那位小姐的事情
I overheard everything just now.
剛才我在旁邊都聽到了
However, I would like to hear it directly from you, Polka.
但我想聽波爾卡你親口講一講
Let's go to the nearby tatami room.
跟我到旁邊的和室來
Okay…
好…好的
I'm sorry, miss.
不好意思
You can wander around in the courtyard
這位小姐 妳就在院子裡
as you please.
隨便逛一逛吧
Okay.
好的
Why didn't Grandpa show more anger
什麼嘛 爺爺為什麼
towards Polka's behavior?
不對波爾卡表現得更生氣一點
He will get angry soon.
他很快就會發火了吧
Fire… Fire…
著了 著了
It's going to catch fire.
火要著了
Are you practicing as a diviner?
你在做占卜師嗎
I see.
這樣啊
That young lady's distant relative runs a high-end club in Shinjuku.
那位小姐的遠房親戚 是在新宿開高級俱樂部的啊
Yes.
對
Her relative lent me an unused building room.
她的那位親戚 把閒置的大樓房間借給了我
Such a generous person.
真是個豪爽的人啊
Anything else strange?
還有什麼其他奇怪的事情嗎
Something like a friend's drone being caught by the police?
像是我朋友的無人機 被警察捕獲了之類的
What is that all about?
那是什麼玩意
Great,
太好了
it seems like I have managed to fool him.
看起來我似乎糊弄過去了
By the way,
對了
there's something else I want to ask you about.
我還有一件事想問你
What is it, Father?
什麼事 父親
Who are you?
你是誰
What are you talking about, Father?
您在說什麼呢 父親
Oh my, this is really incredible.
哎呀 真是不可思議啊
That face and voice are indeed Polka's.
那副臉孔和聲音的確是波爾卡的
In that case…
既然如此…
But you're not him.
但你不是他
You're not Polka.
你不是波爾卡
I don't understand your words, Father.
我不懂您在說什麼 父親
This doesn't make sense.
您說得簡直不合理啊
Let me remind you
我提醒你一下
not to underestimate me.
不要太小瞧我了
Although I am close to death,
雖然我已經一隻腳踏進棺材了
I am still a person who crawled out of a pile of dead bodies.
但好歹也是從死人堆裡爬出來的
And as a father,
而且我可是一位父親
do I need to have reasons?
我才不管這樣合不合理呢
I see.
這樣啊
Is this what parents are really like?
原來父母是這樣子的嗎
He is my beloved son.
他可是我心愛的兒子喔
Can't you give more money?
你不能再加點錢嗎
Completely different from
跟我所知的“父母”
what I know as "parents".
完全不一樣
You…
你…
I have one more thing to ask you.
我還有件事要問你
Where is the real Polka?
真正的波爾卡在哪裡
Is he still alive?
他還活著嗎
About this…
這件事啊…
What are you doing?
你這是幹什麼
Kazuki and Shizuki might be in danger.
華月和紫月可能有危險
What?
什麼
I have promised someone that
我和人約好了
I will protect those two children,
要保護那兩個孩子
so I have to go there now.
所以我要趕過去了
I will explain everything to you later. Please trust me.
之後我會跟你解釋的 請相信我
Although I couldn't understand what you were saying,
雖然我根本聽不懂你在說什麼
but just go.
但是你快去吧
Thank you.
謝謝
That's not something an ordinary person can do.
那根本不是常人能做出的動作啊
Why not just kill him,
斬了他不就好了嗎
my lord?
主公大人
I am not ruthless enough to be able
我還沒有心狠手辣到
to kill someone who looks exactly like my son.
能夠斬了和我兒子長得一模一樣的人
This is no joke.
這可不是鬧著玩的
Sis Suzuka.
涼火姐姐
Um…
那個
We were exploring in the backyard.
我們在後院裡探險
But my bag disappeared
但是我的包包
and I don't know where it is.
不知道掉到哪裡去了
Don't worry.
別擔心
I will go find it.
我幫你們去找
Really?
真的嗎
Thank you.
謝謝妳
I found it.
我找到了
Isn't this the bag I gave her before?
這不是我以前送給她的那個包包嗎
She really treasures it.
她真的很珍惜呢
You actually managed to sneak in here.
你居然真的潛入進來了
Who are you?
是誰
What did you do with the original owner of that face?
你是怎麼處理那張臉原本的主人的
I burned him.
我把他燒掉了
Even his bones were turned into ashes.
連骨頭都燒成灰了
I… I see.
這…這樣啊
I spent two years preparing for this.
我花了兩年來做準備工作
It took quite a long time.
還挺花時間的呢
If I wanted to make it look like an accident and burn a few people,
如果只是偽裝成事故 燒死幾個人
it would be much simpler.
倒是要簡單許多
For example,
比如說
I could make it look like the fire was caused by those twins playing with fire.
偽裝成是那對雙胞胎玩火造成的
What's wrong?
怎麼了
Nothing.
沒什麼
Not bad.
不錯
It has a great taste
有股很棒的味道呢
that makes me want to burn
讓我迫不及待想要燒掉的
the tender body immediately.
柔嫩肉體的味道
I need to hurry and notify them.
我得快點去通知他們
I should notify Grandpa and Bro Takeru,
通知爺爺以及尊哥哥
Kazuki and Shizuki.
華月和紫月
What's going on? It's so hot.
這是什麼 好燙
The boiler room exploded?
鍋爐房爆炸了
Hey! Where is Miss Suzuka?
喂 涼火小姐在哪裡
Oh, great!
啊 真是太好了
You two are safe and sound.
你們兩個都平安無事
Hurry up and escape!
快點逃啊
Why aren't you moving?
怎麼了
Can't you hear my voice?
你們聽不到我的聲音嗎
Who can…
誰來…
Who can come and save…
誰來救救…
these two children?
這兩個孩子
What's that sound?
什麼聲音
Are you two okay?
兩位沒事吧
Miss Kazuki, Master Shizuki, it's on fire!
華月小姐 紫月少爺 著火了
On fire?
著火了
Quickly come with me to this side!
快跟我到這邊來
Don't…follow him!
不要…跟他走
(TOKYO DETENTION CENTER) Mr. Iwa,
(東京拘留所) 岩先生
that guy is a calamity.
那傢伙可是災厄
Why do we still need to interrogate him?
為什麼還要提審他
We need to break the routine
這次的案件
a little bit in this case.
我們有必要稍微打破一下常規
A little?
稍微嗎
I understand it all.
我都明白的
But this guy
可是這傢伙
is undoubtedly the person
是和我們看到的“那東西”
closest to "that thing" we've seen.
最為接近的人 這一點毋庸置疑
Tena Sorimura.
雪車村天鵶
No, I should call you Phantom Solitaire.
不 我應該叫你“怪人雪天鴉”
The nickname you gave me
你給我取的這個綽號
comes from my real name.
是來自於我的本名
I've gotten used to it recently.
最近我倒是有些聽習慣了
That's great.
那還挺不錯的
I see. I'm interested in it.
原來如此 我很感興趣
Although it is unclear whether it was accidental or intentional,
不知是偶然還是必然
the cause of the fire has been determined to be
但這起火災已經確定
from the calamity, the Firestarter.
出自災厄當中的“赴火之蟲”之手
That guy usually leaves behind eerie crime statements at the scene,
那傢伙通常會在現場留下 詭異的犯罪聲明
"This world is a buggy program",
“This world is a buggy program”
which also appeared
“這個世界滿是虛偽”
without exception at the site of the fire.
而這句話同樣出現在了那次火災現場
And without exception,
而且遭受那傢伙毒手的地方
the fire will spread astonishingly quickly
無一例外
in every one of the locations that he has targeted.
火勢都會以驚人的速度蔓延
So I made a hypothesis that
所以我做了個假設
the guy disguised himself as relevant personnel
那傢伙是扮成了相關人員
and spent a long time setting up the crime tools bit by bit,
然後花費了很長時間 一點一點地佈置作案工具
just like insects hide their bodies
這簡直就和隱藏身影
while eating away at houses.
不斷蠶食房子的蟲子一樣
As a result, flames will suddenly burst out.
這樣一來 火焰就會突然噴出
Come over here!
快到這邊來
There is a shelter passage leading to the outside here.
這裡有通往外面的避難通道
Hmm.
嗯
Kazuki, why did you stop?
華月 妳怎麼停下了
Let's hurry up and go over there.
我們抓緊時間離開吧
No, there shouldn't be any
不 這裡的地下
shelter passages underground here.
應該是沒有任何避難通道的
No,
不
it has always been there, young lady.
一直都有的 大小姐
It took me two years to build.
是我花了兩年的時間修建的
I finally caught up.
我總算是趕上了
Although I can't see you,
那個 雖然我看不見妳
please rest assured that
但是請妳放心
Polka and I will protect these two children.
我和波爾卡會保護這兩個孩子的
Wow, you're quite sturdy.
哇 你還挺結實的嘛
It's because this skin is very thick.
因為這張皮做得很厚
Originally, I only planned to taste these twins today,
我今天原本是打算 只品嚐這對雙胞胎的
but unexpectedly, a big meal was delivered right to my front door.
沒想到卻有大餐送上門來
It seems that Polka was right after all.
看來波爾卡說中了呢
Monitoring you was absolutely correct.
監視你果然沒錯
Okay, hurry up and escape to the top.
好了 你們快逃到上面去吧
B-But…
可…可是
Hurry.
快呀
Let's go.
我們走
Mister,
大叔
we are the same kind of people, right?
你跟我是一類人吧
You should know me, right?
你應該認識我吧
The Assassin Hunter, Zaki.
“殺手獵人”咲
I've seen you before when I was scouting out
以前我在克拉麗莎的店裡“踩點”時
It turns out I was right.
果然沒錯
You were wary of me when we had a conflict
畢竟我們 在波爾卡住的大樓裡起衝突時
in the building where Polka stayed.
只有你在提防著我呢
So I was exposed because of this.
原來我是因為這樣曝露的啊
But why are you
不過話說回來
with Polka Shinoyama?
為什麼妳會跟四乃山波爾卡在一起
Did Rozan hire you?
是呂算僱用妳的嗎
It's a little different.
稍微有點不一樣
I'm not telling you.
我才不告訴你呢
Idiot.
蠢貨
Are you human?
妳真的是人嗎
Speaking of which, I thought
話說回來 我本以為
you would definitely go after those two kids.
你肯定會去追逃走的那兩個孩子
But why didn't I do that?
妳問我為什麼沒有那麼做
That's because
那自然是因為
they couldn't escape anymore.
他們已經逃不掉了
You will be buried in the fire with those two little brats.
妳就和那兩個小鬼一起葬身火海吧
Lower your body a bit.
你把身子壓低一些
Maybe this is retribution.
也許這就是我們的報應吧
Sis Suzuka
涼火姐姐
must be angry.
她生氣了吧
No way.
沒那回事
Is it really like that?
真的是那樣嗎
After all, her death was our fault.
畢竟她的死都怪我們
Sister is angry, right?
姐姐生氣了吧
If we can see sister,
如果能見到姐姐
let's apologize to her together, Shizuki.
我們一起向她道歉吧 紫月
Hmm.
嗯
Sis Suzuka?
涼火姐姐
Great,
太好了
I made it this time.
我這次趕上了
Polka?
波爾卡
Didn't the diviner tell you before?
那個占卜師不是說過嗎
You still have a future.
你們還有未來
Besides,
另外
she's not angry with you.
她並沒有生你們的氣
Miss Suzuka
涼火小姐
has been caring about you all along.
一直關心著你們
Where is the fire truck?
消防車呢
They said it would be here soon!
說是馬上就到
Miss Kazuki! Young master Shizuki!
華月小姐 紫月少爺
Thank goodness you are both safe.
幸好你們平安無事
Alright, now it's time for us
好了 現在是時候到我們
to clean up and deal with the aftermath
對這場無妄之災
of this senseless disaster.
進行善後了
The Firestarter should have finished his business by now.
“赴火之蟲”那傢伙 現在應該已經辦完那事了吧
That stubborn old man, Rozan
呂算那個頑固老頭
dared to make me lose face in front of everyone.
竟敢讓我在眾人面前出醜
Then you can cry while smelling the burnt
你就聞著自己後代燒焦的臭味
smell of your own offspring.
一邊哭 一邊去死吧
This is impossible.
這不可能
I have arranged everything perfectly.
我佈置得應該很完美才對
After I left, everything would be burnt.
我先暫時離開這裡 之後再一口氣燒個乾…
Where are you going?
你要去哪裡
Young master Polka.
波爾卡少爺
You're safe.
您平安無事啊
There's no need to deceive me.
用不著糊弄我
Your soul's color hasn't changed.
你靈魂的顏色沒有改變
And yesterday,
而且昨天
my attention was all on that pair of twins, so I didn't notice it.
我的注意力都在 那對雙胞胎的身上 所以沒能察覺到
It seems like there are a lot of people who hate you.
不過好像有很多人都恨著你啊
Give it back…
還回來
My face…
我的臉…
Your voice has turned back to that of a man.
你變回男人的聲音了
That was really close just now.
剛才真是好險啊
I thought I was going to die from lack of oxygen.
還以為我要因缺氧而死了
My cross-dressing was actually exposed twice.
我的變裝居然兩次都被識破了
Stop being so stubborn.
少在那裡嘴硬了
If I had enough magic,
若是魔力充足
I would spend a hundred years torturing you to death.
我必定花費百年的時間將你折磨致死
It's so scary.
好可怕啊
You're just pretending.
裝模做樣的
You're like a middle school student who has just awakened their superpowers.
你簡直就像是 剛覺醒超能力的中學生一樣
You remind me of
你讓我想起了
when I first learned how to control flames.
我自己剛掌握操縱火焰的方法的時候
Fire is very scary, isn't it?
火很可怕吧
So you people have nothing to be afraid of.
所以 你們這些人就沒什麼好怕的了
No matter who you are,
無論你們是什麼人
in the end, you will all succumb to the flames.
最後都將屈服在火焰的面前
I won't say goodbye to you all.
我不會跟你們道別
Bugs are very tenacious.
蟲子可是很頑強的
No matter how you try to eliminate them, they will continue to emerge endlessly.
不管你怎麼消滅 牠們都還是會源源不絕地冒出來
Can my remaining magic break through this firewall?
我剩餘的魔力能夠突破這道火牆嗎
There are two people on the other side of the firewall?
火牆的對面有兩個人
This color is…
這個顏色是…
Lemmings.
“旅鼠軍團”
Huh? Why is he here?
奇怪 他為什麼會出現在這裡
Does that mean he wants us to keep it secret for him?
是要我們替他保密的意思嗎
What's going on?
這究竟是怎麼一回事
Ta-Takeru.
尊…尊
The arsonist who teamed up with you
和你聯手的縱火犯
is now being escorted back to the police station by the police.
如今正在被警察押送回警局
How is that possible? Ah no,
怎麼可能 不
I know nothing about this matter.
我對此事一無所知
Dra-Dragon King's Palace Agency.
龍…龍宮機關
I don't remember giving it
我可不記得
such an exaggerated title.
自己曾取過這般誇張的名號
I just gathered together the people responsible for doing dirty work
我不過是將四乃山集團各個部門裡
from various departments of the Shinoyama Group.
“負責幹髒活”的人聚集在一起罷了
W-Wait.
等…等一下
I was being threatened by the Firestarter.
我是被赴火之蟲威脅的
I see.
原來如此
Then there's no other way.
那就沒辦法了
You have become so foolish.
你已經愚蠢到了這種地步
No wonder you dared to go against the entire family.
怪不得會妄圖和我們整個家族作對
There was a lie in the intelligence
你剛才所說的情報中
you just mentioned.
有一處對我撒了謊吧
You seem to know it very well.
你倒是蠻清楚的
Someone who is good at disguises?
擅長變裝的人
Spending a long time setting up traps at home?
花費漫長的時間在家中佈置機關
You're lying to me.
才不是呢 完全不對
That's not right!
根本就不是那樣
He's just a common criminal
那不過是個作惡的普通人
who committed crimes out of pure malice.
他只是單純的犯罪分子而已
He's not the calamity that you mentioned.
並非你們口中的“災厄”
What can be called a calamity are those who, as humans,
能被稱為災厄的應該是
are able to do things far beyond human capabilities without relying on magic.
身為人類 卻能不靠魔法 就做出遠超人類範疇的事情的那些人
No.
不
Or rather,
應該說他們做出的事
what they do is no different from magic.
和魔法沒什麼區別
Moreover,
而且
The Firestarter must have left behind
赴火之蟲必定會在 犯罪現場留下的文字
a second-half text at the crime scene that only the police knew about.
應該存在只有警方才知道的下文
However,
然而
the scenes you just mentioned
剛才你口中的那一連串現場當中
did not include the second half of the text.
並沒有出現文字的下文
Am I right?
我說的沒錯吧
How did you find out about this matter?
你是怎麼查到這件事的啊
Damn.
可惡
I'll find a chance to burn it all down, including the car and the people here.
我找個機會連車帶人一起燒掉算了
No… No way!
不…不會吧
This world is a buggy program.
這個世界滿是虛偽
C-Could it be…
難…難道是
So it cries out for the flames.
故而 我渴盼火焰
Th-The real Firestarter.
真…真正的“赴火之蟲”
Be, be, be, ho-ho-honest.
老老老實實實實點點點
Fake, tra-trash. Garbage bug, lier, fake.
冒牌貨垃圾垃圾 垃圾蟲騙子假貨
The fake one
冒牌蟲子
must be eliminated.
必須被除掉
It's so hot. What's going on?
好燙 怎麼回事
Hot, hot!
好燙 好燙
What's going on?
什麼情況
Go outside the car quickly!
快到車外去
What exactly
究竟
happened?
發生了什麼事
That child was completely soaked through
那孩子渾身濕淋淋
and crying under the willow tree
在柳樹底下哭泣
in the drizzling rain.
淅淅瀝瀝嘩啦嘩啦啦啦啦
(Episode 7: The Magician)
(第7集 The Magician -魔術師-)